University of Arizona Cooperative Extension Service collection, 1914 -
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Cooperative Extension Service collection, 1914-
MS 344
University of Arizona. Cooperative Extension Service
3.6 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The University of Arizona Cooperative Extension Service was formed in 1915 under the provisions of the Federal Smith-Lever Act. As a division of the University of Arizona College of Agriculture the goals of the Cooperative Agricultural Extension Service are to provided instruction regarding farming and home economics for the improvement of farming practices and production; in short, to make scientific discovery and methods available to the public. By the 1930's weekly publications from the Extension Service regarding issues of economic change and dry farming agriculture were widely distributed for the benefit of Arizona farm families. The Extension Service also assists in 4-H projects; Indian reservation outreach education; assists in forming organized homemakers clubs; and supports community based agricultural projects.
Organization
This collection is organized into two subgroups:
Subgroup I: Papers, 1915-1989
Subgroup II: Photographs, 1948-1977
Scope and Content Note
The Papers in the first subgroup include: annual reports; narrative reports; various publications; legal papers; financial records; business correspondence, and personnel records.
The second subgroup contains photographs. These photograph pertain to a variety of subjects related to Extension Service activities including: group portraits taken at annual conventions; projects under taken on Arizona Indian Reservations; 4-H club activities; slide images taken for TV public service project; and photographs and slides taken of Extension offices throughout Arizona..
Separated Material
The initial accession came in seven boxes. Because of redundant materials within the collection, as well as materials already held in Special Collections, the size of the original accession was reduced from 7 linear feet to 3.6 linear feet.
Access Terms
University of Arizona. Cooperative Extension Service.;; Arizona -- Tucson; Correspondence; Photographs
Container List
- Subgroup I: Papers, 1969-1987
  Contains annual reports, narrative reports, and production & marketing reports related to the activities of the Cooperative Extension Services. Typical subject matter includes: agriculture and natural resources; community development; home economics; 4-H youth and community meeting updates. These materials are bound with covers. The Annual Reports have table of contents.
  - Reports, 1969-1987
    - Annual Report. 1977 and 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual Report. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report. 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Narrative Report. 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Narrative Report. 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Narrative Report. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Narrative Statement -- State Plan of Work. 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Production and Marketing Report. 1969-1971. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Publications, 1915-1984
    Contains a variety of Cooperative Extension Service publications and publication related materials including: staff and faculty bibliography; brochures, flyers and announcements; newsletters, Arizona Extension Service Review, etc.; working drafts of manuscript for the publication College of Agriculture a Century of Discovery, 1985 and photocopies of images; miscellaneous papers and correspondence; and historical documents regarding the formation of the Cooperative Extension Service.
    - Staff and Faculty Bibliographies. 1915-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Brochures, Flyers and Announcements. 1950-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Serving Arizona. 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Arizona Extension Service Review. 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Arizona Extension Service Review. 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Arizona Extension Service Review. 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - College of Agriculture Newsletter. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Arizona Extension Service Review. 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Early Years of Agricultural Extension (1984). 1914-1922 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Meeting the Challenge of the Great Depression (1984). 1922-1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Service Through a Period Without War (1984). 1952-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - More Food and Fiber From Arizona Farms... (1984). 1937-1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Serving in the Shadow of Vietnam... (1984). 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Seeking Normalcy in the Midst of Minority and Other.... 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Publication Planning Papers. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Photocopies of Photographs for Chapters one and two. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Photocopies of Photographs for Chapters three and four. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Manuscript, The College of Agriculture Serves Arizona. No Date (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous: Arizona Farm News, Centennial memo, etc. 1961-1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Extension History, on Paper and on (4) Vinyl Audio Records. ca.1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Legal Papers, 1915-1989
    Contains a variety of papers including: legal/historical documents; Legislative Bills and regulations; financial documents; business correspondence; and personnel records.
    - Legal, Historical documents related to Extension Service. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Laws, Regulations, and Bills. 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Laws, Regulations, and Bills. 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Financial, Funding Comparisons by the State. 1915-1980s (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Financial, County Budget Comparison. 1955-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Financial, Apportionment of Funds. 1959-1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Financial, Rio Rico Retreat. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Business Correspondence/Memos Arizona Council of Cooperative Extension Boards. 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Personnel Lists, Appointments, etc.. 1915-1940 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Personnel Extension Rosters. 1922-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Personnel Recprds. Appointments and Resignation Records. 1940-1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Personnel Service/Time Use Study. 1946 and 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Subgroup II: Photographs, 1976-1989
  Contains photographs from a variety of Extension Service activities including: group portraits from annual conferences; Indian reservation farming projects; slides of the activities of the 4-H club; Cooperative Extension TV pubic announcement images; and slides and photographs of Cooperative Extension offices throughout Arizona.
  - Photographs from Anual Conferences. 1948-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album of Indian Reservation Projects. ca. 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographic Slides from 4-H Club Activities. 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Slides of Cooperative Extension TV Announcement. 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photographs and Slides of Extension Offices Throughout Arizona. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)